(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Hoi!
Ah!
Got one.
I'm Gawr Gura,
and you're watching Gura Channel.
Du du du du du du... tada!
Jan!
Nah, you can't get me in here.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha.
おはようございます！
Good morning!
どうも、サメです！
I'm a shark!
Let's add some blue here
for my hair.
We're gonna go accuracy
just cause it's me
and I know how to draw myself the most, I would say.
Oh dear,
after I've just messed up. That's fine.
Uhh...
Hola amigos!
Hello friends!
¿Cómo... cómo te llamo?
What... what is your name?
¿Do you gusta nacho fries?
Do you like nacho fries?
¿Gusta es nacho fries?
Do you like these nacho fries?
ME GUSTA
I LIKE IT
JA JA JA JA JA JA
HA HA HA HA HA HA
Hello everyone!
Listen, listen! Welcome to the very first episode of...
...hololive Trivia with yours truly, Gura!
第二回の予定は未定です
There are currently no plans for a second edition.
Lasers are included.
Uh, today we have some wonderful guests! Shall we meet them? I think we shall.
Hello, guests!
マリンです！
It's Marine!
ぺこらぺこ！
Pekora peko!
And we have one more special guest!
イナニ！
Ina-ni!
イナネェ！
Ina-ne!
Hi.
かわいい。ぬいぐるみフォルム。
Cute. Plushie form.
Yes, I'll be joining you today, kind of lead you through the program.
Let's get started right away, shall we?
始めましょうか？
Shall we start?
お願いします！
Let's do it!
So, in order to learn more about hololive, we put this show together...
...called hololive Intro Quiz!
イントロドン！
Intro Quiz!
Yes, we'll play the intro of some of the hololive songs...
...very short amount of them.
And you'll have to guess what it is, Gura.
And we'll have Marine-senpai and Pekora-senpai help you kind of guess what the song is.
サポートします！
I'll support you!
任せなさい！
Leave it to me!
Alright, so with that...
...let's play the song!
ハ！ドドン！
Ha! Dodon!
イージーゲーム！
Easy game!
Stellar Stellar!
星街すいせい！
Hoshimachi Suisei!
正解！ナイス！
Correct! Nice!
あれ、意外に長かったね。
That was unexpectedly long.
イントロ長いぺこ。
The intro is long peko.
Alright, alright! How about next song?
ネクチャ！
Next one!
VIOLET by Ina-niis!
正解！
Correct!
あ、ご本人！
Ah, the person herself!
ご本人登場！
The person herself appears!
簡単すぎるぺこなのかなぁ。
Maybe it's too easy.
It's been... it's been too easy right now.
I wonder if we'll have some difficult questions.
もっと短くていいぺこ。Give us next challenge!
Shorter is fine. Give us next challenge!
Number three!
あ、声でわかった！
Ah, knew it by the voice!
Oh! Do you know this one?
I know that voice anywhere.
Aqua-senpai!
Akua Iro Palette!
正解！ナイス！
Correct! Nice!
Nice!
Very good, very good! Alright, alright!
Let's see if the next one is even more challenging.
Let's go!
これ難しい！声がなかったから。わかるかなぁ？
This is hard! There's no voice. Will she know it?
That was a really hard one. Um...
I can feel it... Can I feel it?
ヒント！ヒント！
Hint! Hint!
手を挙げて！
Raise your hands!
ナイス！正解！
Nice! Correct!
Blue... Blue... Blue...
Blue Clapper!
ナイス！正解！
Nice! Correct!
You got them all right! Nice!
Last one! Lasto!
Last one! Final!
Hit me! Okay.
わかったわかった！
I know it, I know it!
絶対ぺこら先輩！
Definitely Pekora-senpai!
ぺこらんだむぶれいん！
Pekorandom Brain!
ナイス！正解！
Nice! Correct!
ぺこらんだむふれいん！ / 兎田ぺこら
Pekoranda Mufurein! / Usada Pekora
Lyrics: 畑亜貴 Composition: 俊龍
Lyrics: Aki Hata Composition: Shunryu
ナイス、ナイス！
Nice, nice!
♪期待したい、大正解
♪Expectations, a big correct answer
♪感動したい、満点さ
♪Wanna be moved, it's a perfect score
♪覚えてないんだ、昨日のことなんて
♪I don't remember things like yesterday
♪食べちゃえ！
♪Eat it up!
ナイスいくぞー！ナイス、ナイス、ナイス！
Nice, here we go! Nice, nice, nice!
♪笑えない、泣いちゃうな、束の間だ
♪Can't laugh, I'll cry, it's just a moment
♪束の間だ、ほい！
♪Just a moment, hoi!
That was actually all the songs we had and Gura, you got them all right!
Yeah! Nice support!
Nice support! Nice support!
どういたしまして！
You're welcome!
Alright, alright, let's move on to the next program, shall we?
次のプログラムは...
The next program is...
hololive Member Posing Challenge!
hololive Member Posing Challenge / ホロメン決めポーズ対決
hololive Member Posing Challenge
おお、ポージング！おおー！
Oh, posing! Ooh!
What this one will be is that a hololive member's name will be shown on the screen.
You will see a picture of a hololive member. Strike a pose that you associate with them!
You'll have to think of a pose that perfectly describes the hololive member.
ホロメンがどんなポーズをするか...
What kind of poses the Holo-members do...
Easy game!
So I'll give you a short countdown and you'll have to make the pose of the hololive member.
Are we ready?
Okie-dokie!
First member is...
キアラ！小鳥遊キアラちゃん！
Kiara! Takanashi Kiara-chan!
Ready? 3, 2, 1... Kiara!
おれ、尻出してるペコですけど...
I'm sticking my butt out though...
違うやろ二人ともそれ何すか？
That's not it, right? What are you two doing?
It's chicken! Chicken!
チキン持ってんじゃねぇか普通に！
You're just holding a chicken!
Ok, ok.
Marine-senpai and Gura, Kikiriki!
Kikiriki! Kikiriki!
Alright, alright.
If I had to give a point...
I'm sorry Pekora-senpai, I'm sorry, but I'm gonna have to go with Marine-senpai and Gura here.
チキン覚ましてんじゃねぇよ！
Don't ignore the chicken!
Alright, alright, I'll give you another chance. Alright.
Next member.
カリー！
Calli!
Alright, alright, let's see, let's see if you guys got this. Alright.
3, 2, 1... go!
Yo, yo! Rap!
Calli's rapping pose!
マリリンはこれ、カマ持ってるんですけど。
Marilyn's holding her scythe here.
She's holding her scythe. Yes.
Yo, yo, yo!
Alright, alright. I'm gonna have to go with Pekora-senpai and Gura.
Wow, how about the next one?
ぐら！ぐらだ！
Gura! It's Gura!
Ready? 3, 2, 1... go!
おかしいだろ！おい！
That's wrong! Hey!
Sha-sha-shark! Shark!
お刺身みたいペコだろお前のは！
Yours looks like sashimi, peko!
お刺身みたい！
Looks like sashimi!
We are shark! Shark!
Yeah! I'd have to go with Pekora-senpai and Gura, but brownie points for Marine.
お刺身！お刺身！
Sashimi! Sashimi!
おらやめろー！
Hey, stop it!
Okay, next member.
イナ！イナちゃん！
Ina! Ina-chan!
Ok, ok. I'll be the judge for this one. Ok.
Alright, 3, 2, 1... go!
え？ぐら？
Eh? Gura?
寝ちゃったよ！
She fell asleep!
Bloop and... PAIN! Bloop and pain!
ぶっぷあんどぺいん！イラスト、ピクチャー！
Bloop and Pain! Illustration, picture!
むにむにテンタクル！むにむにテンタクル！
Mufunny tentacles! Mufunny tentacles!
I'm taking a nap.
昼寝してた！？
Taking a nap!?
昼寝してた！？そうゆう事！？
Taking a nap!? That's it!?
Ina, which one is best? I have to go with Gura.
Yeah!
勝てない、勝てないこれには！
I can't win, I can't win against this!
お昼寝か！理解が足りなかった！
A nap! I didn't have enough understanding!
Okay, how about the next one?
あめ！ワトソン！アメリアちゃん！
Ame! Watson! Amelia-chan!
3, 2, 1... go!
ちょっと手が写ってない...
The hands aren't showing...
指が！指が見えてないから！
The fingers! Because you can't see the fingers!
これは虫眼鏡をやってるんでしょうが！
I'm doing the magnifying glass though!
見て見て、ぺこら！
Look, Pekora!
見て見て！こうです。
Look! It's like this.
あれ、ぐらちゃんとマリン同じなんか？
Wait, are Gura-chan and Marine doing the same one?
同じ？
The same?
ああ、同じ同じ。
Ah, the same, the same.
虫眼鏡！
Magnifying glass!
二人わかってない、わかってない。
You two don't get it, don't get it.
ぺこらは...
Pekora is...
FPSならアメっちゃと言ったでしょ。
I said if it's FPS, it's Ame-chan.
ああ、なるほど。うん、アメちゃん大好きだから。
Ah, I see. Yeah, because she loves FPS.
Ame really likes FPS games. Ah, mushimegane.
Ame really likes FPS games. Ah, magnifying glass.
FPS? Hmm. I'll have to go with Pekora-senpai...
...'cause Ame doesn't really use this very often.
アメちゃんあんまり使ってないんですよね、これ。
Ame-chan doesn't really use this, does she?
あれちょっと。
Wait a minute.
ということはFPSかな？
So maybe it's FPS?
ああ、あまり使ってなかった。
Ah, she hasn't used it much.
お飾り虫眼鏡。
Decorative magnifying glass.
Okay, are you ready for the next number? Dadun!
Whoo! Yeah! Flare! Demo tashika ni...
Whoo! Yeah! Flare! But certainly...
どのポーズ？フレアスポーズ？
Which pose? Flare's pose?
Image de, image de. 3, 2, 1, Go!
Imagine it, imagine it. 3, 2, 1, Go!
何それ？何それ？
What is that? What is that?
ぐら？ぐら何それ？
Gura? Gura, what is that?
Okay, version...
大丈夫？大丈夫？
Are you okay? Are you okay?
アデミル喰らえ...
Artemis Strike...
アデミル喰らえね。はいはい。
Artemis Strike, right. Okay.
Ah, okay. Pekora-senpai and Marine-senpai.
アイドルさん！アイドルさん！アイドルさん！きゅん！
Idol-san! Idol-san! Idol-san! Kyu~n!
Kyu~n pose. I can't choose!
Okay, a draw for this one. A draw.
A draw!
So, what about the next one? Dadun!
お、ノエルね！ノエル。
Oh, Noel, right! Noel.
That's the part... muzukashii yo.
That's the part... it's hard.
Think of the same pose. 3, 2, 1, Go!
何だっけ？何とか...メトロノーム！
What was it? Something... Metronome!
まっするメトロノーム！まっするメトロノーム！
Muscle Metronome! Muscle Metronome!
Muscle Metronome for Pekora-senpai and Marine-senpai.
これ？ぐらは...
This? Gura is...
Kimyou na ugoki. Kimyou move.
Bizarre movement. Bizarre move.
ああ、まっする！まっする！
Ah, muscle! Muscle!
Hore mo sa... I can't choose, yeah.
This one too... I can't choose, yeah.
Okay, I'll have to give it to the senpais here. Sorry girl.
さすが！頑張ったのに。
As expected! Even though I tried hard.
You get brownie points for being cute, okay?
Okay, what about... ready for this one? Dadun!
ああ！オーケー、オーケー。それしかねえわ。
Ah! Okay, okay. That's the only one.
Let's see. 3, 2, 1, Go!
お前ふざけるなよ！お前毎回ケツ出すな！
Don't mess with me! Stop showing your butt every time!
ラビットテイル！ラビットテイル！
Rabbit Tail! Rabbit Tail!
またのやるんじゃないだろお前！
You're doing it again, aren't you!?
Ah, Bun Bun Cha, beko.
うさぎぺこでしょ。お前のケツ...ケツ出さねえよ、ぺこちゃんは。
It's Usagi-peko. Your butt... Peko-chan doesn't show her butt.
Nani Gura sore? Ah, Bun Bun Cha!
What's that, Gura? Ah, Bun Bun Cha!
ああ、カヨぺと一緒にじゃないか！
Ah, isn't it the same as Kayo-pe!
船長も同じじゃないですか。
Isn't Senchou doing the same thing too?
え、これ？違うよ、これは...ラビットテイル。
Eh, this? No, this is... Rabbit Tail.
ラビットテイルいってべこやったことねえべこだから！
I've never done Rabbit Tail-peko!
All right. Dore?
All right. Which one?
Ya, iru to honnin tte koto wa... honnin iru n desu kedo, chotto are wa chotto...
Well, the actual person is here... though she's here, that's a bit...
え、嘘でしょ？そんなことしないよ、ぺこら。
Eh, no way? Pekora doesn't do things like that.
するべこ！するべこ！そんなんしない。
You do-peko! You do-peko! No, she doesn't.
Demo Bun Bun Cha ga motto kakkoii, kakkoii.
But Bun Bun Cha is cooler, cooler.
Very cool. Cooler pose. Bun Bun Cha.
Bun Bun Cha. Demo jissai no Bun Bun Cha wa konna n ja nakute, motto konna kanji kara.
Bun Bun Cha. But the real Bun Bun Cha isn't like this, maybe it's more like this.
ぐら！同じかない？何でそれよ！
Gura! Isn't it the same? Why that!?
こんな感じだわ。確かにそういう感じだわ。
It's like this. Certainly, it's like that.
All right, all right. Hai, you ready for the last one? Last one! Dadun!
All right, all right. Okay, you ready for the last one? Last one! Dadun!
ああ！お願いします！わかりました。
Ah! Please! I understand.
Okay, okay, everyone got it? I think everyone's got the same one.
All right. 3, 2, 1, Go!
ああ！
Ah!
出航！宝鐘マリンす！宝鐘マリンす！
Setting sail! Houshou Marine-su! Houshou Marine-su!
揃った！
We matched!
Yay! Yatta!
Yay! We did it!
Yes! Well, that'll be it for all the pose games. Last of the very all. That... yippee!
Mina! Thank you! Yay! Tanoshikatta.
Everyone! Thank you! Yay! That was fun.
All right, so you guys ready for the next part of the program?
おい！おう！
Oi! Oh!
All right, let's go to the next show, which is... I'm gonna get naked.
Employee of the month
Ladies and gentlemen, now that we're in the air, I would like to direct your attention...
...to the safety instructions in front of you.
Safety Instructions / oh nyo
Should we find ourselves in a...
If the plane's going down, tuck your head between your knees.
Whoa!
Just don't worry about it. It's just... it's just... oh! It's just turbulence. Don't worry.
think about it.
It's like watching Animal Planet.
Dirt
by Gawr Gura
Look down between your toes.
Fellow earthling, what do you see?
Is it brown?
Is it mushy?
Is it dry?
This is called dirt.
Do you know how many organisms live inside the dirt?
Dirt.
As my mom once said, "Dirt Don't Hurt."
Dang it really tingles.
Showing Off My Room
Oh hey, didn't see you there.
Want to take a tour inside my bedroom?
You do? Cool.
Alright, let's go. Follow me this way. Whushaa!
Actually, we're gonna check out my gamer PC first.
You want to see how cool it is?
Check that baby out!
That's got eight billion cores.
Did you know that? It's pretty cool, yeah I know.
Did I build it myself? Of course I did. Gura PC gamer Gura.
Anyway, look at my sofa.
I spent ungodly amounts of time on this sofa right here.
Could you believe that? I bet you could.
Um, if you're asking yourself, "Gura, where is the Ina pillow?"
Um, it's currently in the wash.
It's gonna... it's coming back, it's in the wash.
Don't speculate.
Okay, now I want to show you my... ti-ti-ti-ti-ti, hutcha!
Fish tank! My Ebi fish tank.
Full of scrum-diddly-umptious Ebi.
And for those of you that would like to join the fish tank...
...after the end of today's program...
...there's going to be a form you can fill out and you have to sign.
It's like a health waiver but it's permanent for the rest of your lives. Um...
Oh, there's my box of stuff too. Well, my multiple boxes of stuff actually.
Including... I actually have no idea what's in those, but my trident's there.
It's charging. Neptune said never to touch a charging trident...
...because it messes with the power imbalances.
I don't know what that means but I didn't ask him to expand on it.
Hya!
Okay, now, my clothes.
Look at that!
They look like they're made of paper. That's because I used an iron for the first time...
...and I have no idea how to use an ironing board.
But I think they look alright 'cause there's no wrinkles in them.
Okay, now you want to see my table?
It's a table full of stuff. There's panties in this drawer.
Oh, that's a photo of me. Isn't it great?
Uh, let's pretend I didn't say that.
Anyway, there's an AC control 'cause I get sweaty at night...
...and then there's a fish tank that's also empty...
...because I eat everything inside of it at night.
It's my midnight snack. You have a mini-fridge, I have a fish tank.
So potato-potahto.
My tomato-tomahto.
Ah, you want to see this? Check this out!
Boom boom boom boom Gura Cam! Pew pew pew pew pew pew pew.
Oh my god. Kiara-wa, Auf Wiedersehen.
We have Gawr Gura. Domo. We have Calliope Mori. Yoyo.
We have Ninomae Ina'nis. Wah.
And then we have Amelia Watson. (Gremlin noises) Gawr Gura.
Chummy. Yeah.
Oh, I see. Something really cool. Look.
Ah, hah! Feet.
Te-te-te-te. Let's take a closer look at these plushies, shall we?
Hmm, let's start with me.
Domo, Chummy desu. It's me, Small Gura. Small and tiny.
I can take Gura by the rump.
Shake her, shake her, shake all her lunch money out!
No, Gura stop! What are you doing to me, Gura?
Cute. Don't we look alike?
Cheese!
Okay, and then we have Auf Wiedersehen!
Kiara-wa! I feel like shipping Kiara...
...Kiara, Auf Wiedersehen with somebody else who she really likes.
Auf Wiedersehen!
Kikiriki! Could it be?
Yoyo deadbeats, it's me your boy Calliope- Calliope Bomb-son. Ooh.
Chu!
Kyo...
Ki...
Wait, I- Calli- Calliope Mori, what are you doing here?
Chu!
Oh, yabe!
Oh, crap!
Chu chu chu chu chu!
You get the idea. You get the idea, don't you?
I'll put you back here. I'll put you back here. And then we'll go ahead and we'll take...
Amelia Watson and Ninomae Ina'nis-san.
Ina- Ina... What's their ship name called? I'm sure you guys remember. InAme?
This is Ame, this is Ina, and then...
Chu!
Watson, dummy.
Chu chu chu chu chu chu chu!
Oh, sorry girls. Sorry.
Anyway, let's take it back to Goombus. Goombus, Goombus, Goombus, Goombus. Look. Cute now?
Oh, do you want to see this?
Ta-da!
Who's gonna go for a fun ride today, Goomba?
Yo! Ousha!
Not bad, Goombus, for someone who can't drive, wouldn't you say?
I would say, Gura. Ha!
I know.
Anyway, is there anything you'd like to say to the people?
It's time for you to leave. You've overstayed your welcome.
Gura, you can't say that to the guests. They're here to see you.
Oh.
Thank you for coming today and checking out my bedroom. I'll see you again real soon.
Kiss the shark. Kiss the shark.
Okay, it's time for you to go. Goodbye! Goodbye!
Goodbye! Goodbye! Goodbye!
Deep! Boom!
Driving performed by professional(?) on a closed course
Yee-haw!
Let's go!
Headshot!
Ex-shark-inate!
*sorry not a real game lol
Gawr Boost drink. Look at that.
You can crack open a nice icy cold Gawr Boost drink.
Freshly squeezed shark juice that will refresh you. Yes, it's shark flavored.
The Gura flavor specifically. Freshly squeezed, freshly harvested. Yes.
Only for a limited time though, because like I said... I can only...
気まぐれメルシィ
Lyrics: 八王子P, q*Left Composition: 八王子P
Kimagure Mercy
Lyrics: Hachioji P, q*Left Composition: Hachioji P
ほらほら　また始まった
Look, look, it's started again.
得意の自己弁護　言い訳でもねえ
Your favorite self-defense, not even an excuse.
だって
Because...
ほらほら　また始まった
Look, look, it's started again.
ごめんねのキスのパターンって感じ
That "I'm sorry" kiss pattern feeling.
あーに
Oh, please.
いつかは私だけ　そうね夢みたこともあったけど
Someday just me, yeah, I once dreamed of that too.
淋しいときだけ電話して　もう、うんざりだわ
Calling only when you're lonely, I'm already sick of it.
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You have no interest in me at all.
君が好きなのは自分でしょ？
The one you love is yourself, right?
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
As I thought, you have no interest in me.
その話もう聞き飽きたわ
I'm tired of hearing that story.
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you basically have no interest in me.
そうやってまた誤魔化して
Evading like that again.
Be my boy　わがまま過ぎるでしょ
Be my boy, you're way too selfish.
抱きしめてよね
Hold me, okay?
本当君はしょうもないな
You really are hopeless.
重い私もしようがないわ
My heavy love is also unavoidable.
泣いたっていけない、待ったっていけない
Crying won't help, waiting won't help.
期待はしないよ
I won't expect anything.
もう少しだけなら　踊ってもいいかもな
If it's just a little bit more, maybe it's okay to dance.
とろけて　とろけて　生きたいの
I want to live melting away, melting away.
どんなアピールも意味ないし
No matter how I appeal, it's meaningless.
気付いてくれないけど
You won't notice, but...
ぜんぜん私に興味ないじゃん
You have zero interest in me, right?
どこがダメなの教えてよ ねえ
Tell me what's wrong with me, hey!
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
Just as I thought, you have no interest in me.
携帯ばかりいじってさ
You're always just messing around on your phone.
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん
To begin with, you generally have no interest in me.
少しぐらい期待させてよ もう
Give me at least a little hope already!
ロンリーガール 独り占めしてよ
Keep this lonely girl all to yourself.
Baby 振り回さないで
Baby, don't lead me on.
目、目、耳、目、ワン、トゥ、シャッフルダンス踊りましょう
Eye, eye, ear, eye, one, two, let's dance the shuffle dance.
早く手と手つないで サイコに歌って
Hurry and join hands, and sing like a psycho.
溺れるくらい愛してよ
Love me enough to make me drown.
ぜんぜん私に興味ないじゃん
You have zero interest in me, right?
君が好きなのは自分自身でしょ ねえ
The one you love is yourself, isn't it? Hey!
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
Just as I thought, you have no interest in me.
その話、もう聞き飽きたわ
I'm already tired of hearing that story.
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん
To begin with, you generally have no interest in me.
そうやってまた誤魔化しても
Even if you keep deceiving me like that...
ガタガタ言って覚悟はできてるの？
Complaining like that, are you prepared?
きまぐれメルシィ
Kimagure Mercy
お味はいかが？
How does it taste?
愛とは不思議 今から紡ぐ
Love is a mystery, a story...
物語 愛のようなの
...I'm about to spin, like love.
ハンバーガー
A hamburger.
最初は恋を夢見る
At first, dreaming of love...
アメリカンガール
...an American girl.
大好きな食べ物は ハンバーガー
My favorite food is a hamburger.
ああ 愛しのダーリン
Oh, my darling love...
どこにいるの？
...where are you?
恋とは何かな 考えてみよう
What is love? Let's think about it.
ふわふわ熱々 それはまるでバンズ
Fluffy and hot, it's just like the buns.
好きとは何かな 感じてみたいの
What is "like"? I want to feel it.
赤く甘酸っぱい それはまるでトマトケチャップ
Red and bittersweet, it's just like tomato ketchup.
理想のダーリンは シャキシャキレタス
My ideal darling is crisp lettuce.
それでいてパワフルなバーグ
And yet, a powerful burger patty.
素敵！
Wonderful!
でもなんだかほら お腹すいたわ
But look, I'm somehow getting hungry.
お料理しちゃおう そうしよう
Let's get cooking! Let's do it!
じわりこんがりバンズを焼いて
Toast those buns until they're golden brown...
ケチャップでノリノリバーガー
...and make a high-energy burger with ketchup!
大好き好き ハンバーガー
I love, love hamburgers!
素敵 愛 LIKE ハンバーガー
Wonderful! I like hamburgers!
きれいな瞳に映りました
It was reflected in those beautiful eyes.
もう何かが足りないよ、ほら
Look, something's still missing.
でもシンプルが一番ね
But simple is best, after all.
大好き好き ハンバーガー
I love, love hamburgers!
ベイビー 愛 LIKE ハンバーガー
Baby, I like hamburgers!
大好きだよ ハンバーガー
I really love hamburgers.
さぁ いただきましょう ハンバーガー
Now, let's dig in to the hamburger!
密に溶け合って ドキドキする
Melting together closely, my heart pounds.
包み込むぬくもり 噛みしめる幸せ
Enveloped in warmth, savoring the happiness.
ああ 私のダーリン どこですか？
Oh, where is my darling?
デートをしたいな なんて思っていたの
I was thinking that I'd like to go on a date.
ねえ想うだけで チーズのようにとろけちゃいそう
Hey, just the thought makes me melt like cheese.
でも時間来たら バイバイは嫌だよ
But when the time comes, I don't want to say goodbye.
もう離さないで オニオンみたいに 涙が出ちゃう
Don't let go, or I'll cry like an onion.
デートのコースは ドライブがいい
A drive would be a great date course.
目玉焼きの太陽浴びて キラリ
Bathed in the sun of a fried egg, sparkling.
時には甘くて 時には刺激的
Sometimes sweet, sometimes stimulating.
ポテトとマスタード お願い
Potatoes and mustard, please!
じわじわとろり チーズと
Slowly melting cheese...
オニオンまで焼き付いて
...and even the onions are grilled on.
大好き好き ハンバーガー
I love, love hamburgers!
キラリ 愛 LIKE ハンバーガー
Sparkling! I like hamburgers!
きれいな瞳に映りました
It was reflected in those beautiful eyes.
もうボリュームありすぎだわ
It's already got too much volume!
隣で一緒に食べてよ
Eat it here next to me.
大好き好き ハンバーガー
I love, love hamburgers!
カモン 愛 LIKE ハンバーガー
Come on! I like hamburgers!
大好き好きよハンバーガー
I love, love, love hamburgers
大好きよハンバーガー
I love hamburgers
大好き好き好きハンバーガー
I love, love, love, love hamburgers
さぁいただきましょう
Now, let's eat!
食べれどやっぱり
Even if I eat them, as expected...
ダーリンと食べたいな
I want to eat them with you, darling
じわりとんがりバンズは
The slowly toasted pointy buns
キッチンのケチャップで塗れば
If you spread kitchen ketchup on them
踊り出しそうパーティー
It's like they'll start a dancing party
大好き好きハンバーガー
I love, love hamburgers
素敵 I LIKE Hamburger
Wonderful, I like hamburgers
じわじわとろりチーズと
With the slowly melting cheese
オニオン炒めよくばり
And a greedy helping of sautéed onions
バターとマスタード塗って
Spread on butter and mustard
大好き好きハンバーガー
I love, love hamburgers
きらり I LIKE Hamburger
Sparkling, I like hamburgers
大好き好きよハンバーガー
I love, love, love hamburgers
大好きよハンバーガー
I love hamburgers
大好き好き好きハンバーガー
I love, love, love, love hamburgers
さぁいただきましょう
Now, let's eat!
ハンバーガーを頬張りましょう
Let's stuff our faces with hamburgers
大好き好きハンバーガー
I love, love hamburgers
ベイベー I LIKE Hamburger
Baby, I like hamburgers
おなかいっぱい
My stomach is full
こころもいっぱい
My heart is full too
愛こそハンバーガー
Love itself is a hamburger
ごちそうさまでした チュッ
Thank you for the meal! *Mwah*
ニッポン笑顔百景
Nippon Egao Hyakkei
Lyrics/Composition: 前山田健一
Lyrics/Composition: Maeyamada Kenichi
じゅげむ じゅげむ 五劫の擦り切れ
Jugemu, Jugemu, Gokou no Surikire
海砂利水魚の水行末 雲来末 風来末
Kaijarisuigyo no Suigyoumatsu, Unraimatsu, Fuuraimatsu
食う寝る処に住む処
Kuunerutokoro ni Sumutokoro
藪ら柑子の藪柑子
Yaburakouji no Yabukouji
パイポパイポ パイポのシューリンガン
Paipo, Paipo, Paipo no Shuuringan
シューリンガンのグーリンダイ
Shuuringan no Guurindai
グーリンダイのポンポコピーの ポンポコナーの
Guurindai no Ponpokopii no Ponpokonaa no
長久命の長助
Choukyuumei no Chousuke
ヨッ！
Yo!
ちょいと時間を頂きます
Please give me a little bit of your time
ご清聴ください ちょうど良い
Please listen carefully, it's just right
笑う門には福来たり
Good fortune comes to those who smile
お祭り野郎がやって来ます
The festival guys are coming along
ソレ！
Sore!
その心は その心は
And the meaning is, the meaning is...
どちらもハッピーになるでしょう
Either way, everyone will be happy
お後がよろしいようで
That's all for this one
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, come on let's laugh
こんな時代こそ笑いましょう
Especially in times like these, let's laugh
笑わにゃ損損 泣いたら負けだよ
If you don't laugh it's a loss, if you cry you lose
空元気 笑いましょう
With forced courage, let's laugh
波瀾万丈 酸いも甘いも
Through ups and downs, the sour and the sweet
乗り越えたあっぱれ日本人
The splendid Japanese people have overcome it all
笑おう どんな時でも
Let's laugh, no matter when
何くそ笑いましょう
Against all odds, let's laugh
ハハハッ ニョホホッ
Hahaha! Nyohohot!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Just laugh without caring about the mood
エガオッ エガオッ
Smiles! Smiles!
笑う門には福来たる
Good fortune comes to those who smile
皆様、今日はお出でいただきましてありがとうございました
Everyone, thank you so much for coming today
ここでお一つ
And now, for one more thing
ねずみの娘が嫁入りして
A mouse's daughter got married
おうちに帰ってきたんで
And came back home
ねずみのお母さんが大変怒って
The mother mouse was very angry
はんなりところで お前どこへ
In a gentle way she asked, 'Where are you going?'
誰が嫌で 帰ってきたんや
Who did you hate so much that you came back?
いえ 誰が嫌じゃないんですけれど
No, it's not that I hate anyone
お父さんが夜な夜な嫌なの
But I hate what my father does night after night
夜な夜な何が嫌なんじゃい
What is it that you hate night after night?
あぁもう猫のお守りは嫌にゃー
Ah, I'm just tired of guarding the cat!
忙しさに身を任せて
Leaving yourself to the busyness
消えていくなんて野蛮だぜ
Just fading away is barbaric
笑おう 笑おう 笑えなくても
Let's laugh, let's laugh, even if you can't
笑うしかないでしょう 笑おう
There's nothing to do but laugh, right? Let's laugh
口角上げて満面の面
Lift the corners of your mouth for a full-faced smile
笑いましょう
Let's laugh
古今乱大悲劇さえ
Even the greatest tragedies of all time
振り落として現代日本人
Shake them off, modern Japanese people
笑おう 未来永劫
Let's laugh for all eternity
ぐわーっと笑いましょう
Let's laugh with a big 'Gwaa!'
この娘の顔が時々ズレないで
Hope this girl's face doesn't glitch out sometimes
しかめつらなど変な顔
With frowning or strange faces
笑顔見たいから
Because I want to see your smile
笑おう 笑おう さあ笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, come on let's laugh
こんな時代こそ笑いましょう
Especially in times like these, let's laugh
笑わにゃ損損 泣いたら負けだよ
If you don't laugh it's a loss, if you cry you lose
空元気 笑いましょう
With forced courage, let's laugh
波瀾万丈 酸いも甘いも
Through ups and downs, the sour and the sweet
乗り越えたあっぱれ日本人
The splendid Japanese people have overcome it all
笑おう どんな時でも
Let's laugh, no matter when
何くそ笑いましょう
Against all odds, let's laugh
いっとう笑いましょう
Let's laugh our best.
Gura-wa! Nippon-mo!
Gura too! Japan too!
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Don't worry about the atmosphere, just laugh.
笑顔！ 笑顔！
Smile! Smile!
笑う門には福来たる
Good fortune comes to those who smile.
"Best of Gura Album" Now On Sale
Hello. I'm your last brain cell here to tell you it's time to pick up the pencil.
Your exam is due in less than an hour.
And what are you doing? You're watching a 3D shark sing songs to you.
But now you're wondering, is this a dinosaur or is this a shark? I don't really know.
Well, instead of pondering that answer, maybe you should be focusing on your schoolwork.
Thank you for chatting with me. This has been your last brain cell speaking. Bleh!
We're supposed to turn this into like a fine powder and it's not working.
I don't have a rolling pin. I don't have anything.
Just my- my sheer brawn, my gaming grip.
Use the pan?
Plink plonk plink plonk plink plonk!
Today I'm going to be telling you all about acrylic nails.
Yaaaas!
Slay!
Gosh, this is like- this is how I was meant to be.
I don't think so.
Domo! Minna! Chumbuds and new friends!
Welcome to Gura's Quiz Show!
It is not a math prison cell.
Shall we begin?
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Ho-cha! Let us begin.
First question please that I know I'm going to get correct.
Question 1: 3+5=?
Hai!
Yes!
Eight.
Answer: 3+5=8
Oh yes, of course, of course, of course.
Did you doubt me? No? Good. Okay.
Next question!
Question 2: 9x9=?
9 times 9.
Wait, there's the finger thing. Do the finger thing, Gura.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
Wait, that doesn't look right.
I'm gonna trust it anyway.
Hai!
Yes!
Fifty-one.
The finger thing never fails! Ow! Wait, where did that come from?
Okay... um... wait, one, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven... I have nine- ten fingers.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine...
Why did I say fifty-one?!
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
Eighty-one! Eighty-one!
Answer: 9x9=81
Okay, see? I just had a little lapse in brain judgment there.
There's nothing wrong with that, right cameraman? There's nothing wrong with that.
Can I have the next question please? I'm ready.
Question 3: 54-16=?
Fifty-four minus sixteen.
Fifty-four minus ten is forty-four.
Forty-four minus six...
...three, two, one, thirty... twenty-nine, twenty-eight...
Hai!
Yes!
Twenty-eight.
Actually thought I had that one there, wait let me try again.
Fifty-four minus ten... fifty-four minus ten... fifty-four minus ten...
...is forty-four.
Minus six... forty-four, forty-three, forty-two, forty-one, forty, thirty-nine, thir-
Hai!
Yes!
Thirty-eight.
Answer: 54-16=38
So... that ain't so bad, is it, huh?
No, this all-ebi piling up next to me is not so bad, is it?
No, this all-shrimp piling up next to me is not so bad, is it?
Keep 'em coming, keep 'em coming.
Can I have the next question? I'm on a roll.
Question 4: 17x2+3=?
Um... can I use PEMDAS?
PEMDAS is parentheses...
PEMDAS... three plus five is... three plus two... oh, three plus two is five...
...times seventeen is...
...is...
Um... wait, 17 times 5?
5 times... 5 times 7 is...
5 times 7 is 40.
5 times... 7 is 4... 17 times...
I don't remember how to do shorthand multiplication.
This is actually terrible. Um...
They said I wasn't gonna get these questions right,
and I told them that I was gonna get it right,
but it looks like I'm not gonna be able to get it right,
and now there's shrimp flying everywhere. 5 times 17 is...
31?
5?
105!
Gah! I...
Uh... okay, looks like we're back to the drawing board.
17 times 5... 17...
I'm going to write it out. 17 times 5.
5 times 7, I believe is...
I'll say it's 35. Carry the 1.
5 times 1 is 5, 6, 7, 8.
Hah!
85!
Okay, back to the drawing board.
I could have sworn I did that right.
Am I forgetting how to do longhand multiplication?
Or is this shorthand multiplication? I don't know.
5 times 5 is 5... 6, 7, 8.
How is this wrong? How did I get...?
I can't see with all these shrimp everywhere.
How did I get this wrong? How did I get this wrong?
87!
Can I get a hint?
Can I get a hint, please?!
No hints? Okay.
Be that way then. Fine.
5 times 7 is 30. We'll say it's 30 now.
Now it's 30... Carry the 5? 6, 7, 8.
Hah!
80!
わかりません。
I don't understand.
I don't understand, and this is really terrible.
Am I getting this math wrong?
5... please end this torture. Can I have the next question?
Hint, please!
Go from left to right, in order.
17 times 2. Am I just doing my math wrong?
17 times 2. 7 times 2 is 14.
Carry the 1. 2, 3... plus 3 equals...
Hah!
37!
Yeah-da! Hah! Hoi!
Next question.
Ugh... okay.
Um, 6... uh... 6 times 20 is...
6 times 2 is 12, so 6 times 20 is...
...is a hundred... oh god... is 120.
Times... minus 9... wait, okay.
Wait, do I start from the beginning?
For the last one I'm supposed to start for this one.
6 times 20 is... 6 times 20... 6 times 20.
6 times 2 is 12, so 6 times 20 is 120.
Right? Minus 9 is... minus 9...
120 minus 9 is 119... is 109.
109 times 13 is... 1 times... gah!
Hah!
100... 1000... 1000... 1130?
Okay... okay... um, 9... 120 minus 9 is 119...
...times 13 is... 109 minus 13?
109 minus 13 is... oh.
Wait, why are the shrimp getting bigger and then taller and higher?
T-t-t-t... the constant ticking is not helping.
120 minus 9. 20... 120. 19, 18, 17, 16, 15, 14, 13, 12, 11.
Oh, okay. It's 111.
111 times 13 is... Hah!
1113!
Was that what I answered last time? Ah! Okay. Okay.
Wait! Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, okay.
Okay... Uh... Well, that's 100 and... 111.
111 minus... times 13 is...
Ah! What is that? 111 times 13 is...
Hi!
1,213.
1,000...
Hi!
1,412.
You guys! It's not even waiting for me
to get the answer wrong. I mean, right.
Hi!
1,604.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Hi!
Multiplication first. / 掛け算を先にしよう
20 minus 9 is 11, 11 times 6 is 66 times 13.
See, that's an entirely different math equation now.
Thanks, math god.
Could have used that about three minutes ago.
Now I've made a fool of myself
in front of everybody.
Wait, what did I say before? 20 minus...
Now they've just changed the answer,
they said multiplication first.
Well, the guy in my ear doesn't seem
to be getting his information right.
6 times 2... 20... No, we already... Okay, wait.
Oh, wait! I got it! I got it!
6 times 20 is a hundred... Wait, no,
6 times 20 is...
Uh, this is really embarrassing.
120 minus 9 times 13 is...
9 times 13...
9 times 3 is 27... 21? Did I do that right?
9... 10... 11... 111 times 120...
I hope I'll get this right!
Hi!
10,020.
I think I'm gonna...
I think I'm gonna get another hint. Please!
Please!
Multiplication first, then subtraction. / それぞれの掛け算をしてから引き算をしよう
Please! This isn't a hint! This isn't a hint! Please!
10... 120 minus...
120 minus...
Hi! Hi! Hi!
104!
Aah! Boy!
だめですよ！
No way!
Dah!
Hello?
Like, seriously.
Um, okay. It's like, 'Hooked on UwU'.
Reading can weally weally help you like, UwU.
Have like a way better vocabulary.
Like, totally.
Are you looking for a delightful getaway
in the deep forest of the unknown souls?
Well, do I have the perfect vacation home for you.
Locked away 3,000 miles in the deep woods
where no one will hear you scream,
the Mushroom Kings await for your great return.
They've prepared a feast for you,
or maybe you're the feast.
All right, so that wraps up all the
games and quizzes for today.
What'd you guys think? どうでしたか？
What'd you guys think? How was it?
楽しかったでーす！
It was fun!
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you! ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you! Thank you very much!
Thank you! Arigatou gozaimasu!
Thank you! Thank you very much!
I also want to say thank you Ina for...
Thank you, Ina, so much!
Hope you guys had fun.
Yeah, that was... That was really fun.
I hope we can do this again.
また遊びに来てくださいね！
Please come and visit again!
うんうん！また来ますよ！
Yeah! We'll come again!
そうそうそう！
Right, right, right!
Ja, well, I guess that's it for today's program.
Uh, thanks everyone for tuning in!
Thank you everybody!
We had fun too, everybody watching!
Thank you! Thank you!
I hope you had fun too, and I guess we will see...
See you guys...
...next time if we have an episode two.
Ina?
Yes?
取って、取っていいですか？
Can I take it? Can I take it?
何だこれ！？
What is this!?
え、何！？何！？
Eh, what!? What!?
やばい！やばい！
This is bad! This is bad!
お前、お前、誰！？
You, who are you!?
何だこれ！
What the heck is this!
痛い、痛い！
It hurts, it hurts!
助けて！
Help me!
倒せ、倒せ！
Defeat it! Get it!
無理、美味しくないです！
Impossible, I'm not delicious!
助けて、ぺこらちゃん！
Help me, Pekora-chan!
ぺこらちゃん！
Pekora-chan!
Hi everyone! It's the Gura Shoulder Bag!
Oh my god!
With very sharky embroideries...
...matching none other than me, Gawr Gura!
A jacquard-weave shoulder strap...
...which is very trendy and very cool!
Which we've even included.
The inside fabric actually matches that...
...of my very first casual outfit...
...the very cool pattern, yeah!
Gawr Gura! Mmm-hmm.
This bag is perfectly sized for your books...
...or other small belongings...
...as well as perhaps your very own Guar Boost drink!
Alright, that's all from me folks!
Bye-bye!
Viewers Like You
This program was made possible...
...by contributions to Gura...
...from viewers like you.
Thank you.